you don't need college learning learn
stuff okay
everything is available basically for
free
you can learn anything you want for free
it is not a question of learning
um
there there is
a value that colleges have which is like
you know seeing whether somebody's
is can somebody work hard at something
including a bunch of
sort of annoying homework assignments
and still do their homework assignments
uh and and kind of soldier through and
and get it done
you know that's
that's like
the main value of college and then also
you
you know if you you if you probably want
to hang around with a bunch of people
your own age for a while instead of
going right into the workforce
um
so i think colleges are basically for
fun and to prove you can do your chores
but they're not for learning
but there is a requirement of evidence
of exceptional ability
like you just can't if you're trying to
do something exceptional they must have
evidence of exceptional ability i don't
consider going to college evidence of
exceptional ability
in fact
ideally you dropped out and did
something
i mean obviously you know
you look at like you know
gates is a pretty smart guy he dropped
out uh john was pretty smart he dropped
out you know larry ellison smart guy he
dropped out like
obviously not needed
generally you want education to be like
as close to a video game as possible
like a good video game like
you do not need to tell your kid to
play video games they will play video
games on autopilot all day
so if you can make it interactive and
engaging
then then you can make education
far more compelling and far easier to do
so you really want to
disconnect the whole grade level three
thing from the subjects allow people to
progress at the fastest pace that they
can or interested in in each subject
it seems like a really obvious thing
i mean i think like most teaching today
is is a lot like vaudeville
where
um
and it's and as a result it's just not
not that compelling it's like somebody's
standing up there and lecturing to you
and they've done the same lecture
several years in a row they're not
necessarily all that engaged or
in doing it do you agree with peter
thiel about the unnecessariness of
university higher education
a university education is often
unnecessary
that's not to say it's unnecessary for
all people but
i i think
you probably learn about as much or the
vast majority what you're going to learn
there in the first two years
and most of it is from your classmates
now for a lot of companies
they
they do want to see the completion of
the degree because they're looking for
someone who's going to persevere and see
it through to the end and that's
actually what what's important to them
so it really depends on what somebody's
goal is if the goal is to start a
company
i would say no point in finishing uh
college um
so
i think that's how it should be and it
shouldn't be that you've got like these
grades where people move in lockstep
and so everyone
goes through you know goes like normally
you know we'll go through
english math
uh
science and so forth from like fifth
grade to sixth grade to seventh grade
like it's an assembly line uh but but
people are not objects on an assembly
line that's a ridiculous notion so how
would you educate your five boys
actually i created a little school
yeah what kind of school could you
subscribe to us sure it's i mean it's
small it's only got 14 kids now and
it'll have 20 kids in in september
um
it's called ad astra which means to the
stars that's maybe a bit different from
from most other schools is that there
aren't any grades there's no there's no
like not grade one grade two grade three
type of thing and making all the
children go and in the same grade at the
same time like an assembly line i know
um you know because some people love
english or languages some people love
math some people love music
and and different abilities different
times it makes more sense to to cater
the education to match their aptitudes
and abilities i think that's one
principle
another is
that it's important to teach
teach problem solving or teach to the
problem not to the tools
so this would be like
let's say
um
you're trying to teach people about uh
how engines work or you know you could
start by a more a more traditional
approach would be to say we're going to
teach you all about screwdrivers and
wrenches
and
and you're going to have a course on
screwdrivers or caution wrenches and all
these things and it's
this is a very difficult way to do it a
much better way would be like here's the
engine now let's take it apart how we're
going to take it apart oh you need a
screwdriver that's what the screwdriver
is for you need a wrench that's what the
wrench is for
um and then a very important thing
happens which is that the relevance of
the tools because it seems to be going
pretty well
i mean the kids really love going to
school i think that's a a good sign you
know i mean i hated going to school when
i was a kid it was torture
um so
the fact that they
like they actually think vacations are
too long
like they want to go back to school wow
yeah exactly weird i know
if you think you're like what is
education like you're basically
downloading data and algorithms into
your brain
and
it's it's actually
amazingly
bad in conventional education because
like it shouldn't be like this huge tour
like the more you can gamify
the uh the process of learning the
better like
and i think unfortunately like a lot of
education is very bored billion um
you've got
uh
someone standing up there kind of
lecturing at people
um and they've done the same lecture 20
years in a row and they're not very
excited about it and that lack of
enthusiasm you know is conveyed to the
students that they're not very excited
about it they don't know why they're
there like why are we learning this
stuff we don't even know why um in fact
i think a lot of things people learn
probably there's no point in learning
them
because they never use them in the
future
you